<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home Page on Amazon Food Reviews</title><link>https://malthe57.github.io/comsocsci2022_AFR_website/</link><description>Recent content in Home Page on Amazon Food Reviews</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://malthe57.github.io/comsocsci2022_AFR_website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data description</title><link>https://malthe57.github.io/comsocsci2022_AFR_website/data-description/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://malthe57.github.io/comsocsci2022_AFR_website/data-description/</guid><description>The dataset consists of product reviews and metadata of products in the &amp;ldquo;Grocery and Gourmet Food&amp;rdquo; category on Amazon and was collected by researchers at UCSD.
The original reviews dataset has 142.8 million reviews spanning from May 1996 - July 2014. However, we use only use a subset of the dataset where all users and items have at least 5 reviews in the &amp;ldquo;Grocery and Gourmet Food&amp;rdquo; category, called food 5-core.</description></item><item><title>Network analysis</title><link>https://malthe57.github.io/comsocsci2022_AFR_website/network-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://malthe57.github.io/comsocsci2022_AFR_website/network-analysis/</guid><description>We created and investigated two networks: One for the reviewer and one for the products.
Reviewer network
The goal is to identify the so-called super users on Amazon; users who especially active and write many reviews on Amazon.
The review network consists of 14,681 nodes and 4,228,404 edges. Due to the sheer size of the network, it is only possible to visualise a subset. The subset consists of reviewers for 500 unique, randomly sampled products, so the resulting network has a total of 5,773 nodes and 229,767 edges.</description></item><item><title>Text analysis</title><link>https://malthe57.github.io/comsocsci2022_AFR_website/text-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://malthe57.github.io/comsocsci2022_AFR_website/text-analysis/</guid><description>blockquote p { padding:0; margin:100; } The most interesting part of this food review network is of course the reviews themselves, as they contain subjective opinions on different products. Therefore, the main idea is to use the reviews for sentiment analysis, using the labTM dictionary of happiness scores 😏
The words in the labTM dictionary are rated on a continuous scale from 1 (low happiness) to 9 (high happiness), where a happiness score of 5 indicates neutral1.</description></item></channel></rss>